Guide to the Fales Library Events Video Collection 1990-2016 MSS.307
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library Events Video Collection
1990-2015
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library
MSS.307
6.25 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons, 4 manuscript boxes, 1 card box, and 2 shared boxes
59 VHS
153 DVDs
1 DVCAM
2 MiniDV
1 Betamax
1 Digital_Betacam
2 audiocassettes
Historical Note
The Fales Library Events Video Collection contains video and audio of events either arranged by or held at the Fales Library relating to the Fales Library, Fales archival collections and/or the Fales Food Studies Series.
Arrangement
This collection is divided into three series:
1. Fales Events Videos; 2. Fales Food Studies Events; and 3. Submasters (Restricted Access)
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Scope and Content
This collection contains video and audio of events either arranged by or held at Fales Library.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. Access copies are avaialble in Series I and II of the collection.
Accruals
Additional collection material is added regularly.
- Series I: Fales Events Videos, 1994-2015, undated; 3.75 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 4 manuscript boxes, 1 card box, and 1 shared cassette box; 26 VHS; 58 DVDs; 1 DVCAM; 1 Betamax; 1 Digital_Betacam; 2 audiocassettes
  - ACT UP; Read My Lips; Fales Library, Undated; ID: FA0001 (Box 3, Vhs FA0001)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Format: VHS
  - Artist's Circles: What They Do, How Do They Work, Undated; ID: FA0002 (Box 4, Dvd FA0002)
    Format: DVD
  - Campus Flash: Fales Library and Special Collections, Undated; ID: FA0003 (Box 4, Dvd FA0003)
  - The Downtown Show; Creating the Archive, Undated; ID: FA0004 (Box 4, Dvd FA0004)
  - The Downtown Show; The Moving Edge, Undated; ID: FA0005 (Box 4, Dvd FA0005)
  - The Downtown Show; No Alternative, New Downtown Art, Undated; ID: FA0006 (Box 4, Dvd FA0006)
  - The Downtown Show; Readings From the Downtown Book, Undated; ID: FA0007 (Box 4, Dvd FA0007)
  - The Downtown Show; Scholars and Artists 2, Undated; ID: FA0008 (Box 4, Dvd FA0008)
  - The Downtown Show; Simon Reynolds, Rip It Up Start Again, Post-Punk 78-84, Undated; ID: FA0009 (Box 4, Dvd FA0009)
  - Great Books: Alice in Wonderland, Undated; ID: FA0010 (Box 3, Vhs FA0010)
  - Great Books: All Quiet On The Western Front, Undated; ID: FA0011 (Box 3, Vhs FA0011)
  - Six Years After the NEA 4: Karen Finley, John Fleck, Holly Hughes, Tim Miller, Undated; ID: FA0013 (Box 3, Vhs FA0013, Dvcam FA0012)
  - Television is 70 with Dr. Malcolm H.I. Baird, Undated; ID: FA0014 (Box 3, Vhs FA0014)
  - The Making of Alice in Wonderland: Narrated by Lorrie Goulet [Jud 'Alba], 1994; ID: FA0015 (Box 3, Vhs FA0015)
  - Edward Robb Ellis; NYU, November 13, 1996; ID: FA0016 (Box 3, Vhs FA0016)
  - Fales Archive: The Downtown Project; Sharon Mesmer, Max Blagg, October 27, 1998; ID: FA0017 (Box 3, Vhs FA0017)
  - Dr. John Chambers in Fales, November 11, 1998; ID: FA0018 (Box 3, Vhs FA0018)
  - City Arts [512]: David Wojnarowicz. Duke Ellington. Famous Where I Came From, January 29, 1999; ID: FA0019 (Box 3, Vhs FA0019)
  - David Wojnarowicz in Fales [Part 1], February 4, 1999; ID: FA0020 (Box 3, Vhs FA0020)
  - David Wojnarowicz in Fales [Part 2], February 4, 1999; ID: FA0021 (Box 3, Vhs FA0021)
  - Beautiful: The Writing of Dennis Cooper, March 2, 2000; ID: FA0022 (Box 3, Vhs FA0022)
  - Beautiful: The Writing of Dennis Cooper, March 3, 2000; ID: FA0023 (Box 3, Vhs FA0023, Box 6, Dvd FADVD0023)
  - The Tattoed Man Tells All, May 15, 2000; ID: FA0024 (Box 3, Vhs FA0024)
  - Lust for Life: The Writings of Kathy Acker: Panel 1, 2003; ID: FA0025 (Box 3, Vhs FA0025)
  - Lust for Life: The Writings of Kathy Acker: Panel 2, 2003; ID: FA0026 (Box 3, Vhs FA0026)
  - Lust for Life: The Writings of Kathy Acker: Panel 3, 2003; ID: FA0027 (Box 3, Vhs FA0027)
  - Lust for Life: The Writings of Kathy Acker: Panel 4, 2003; ID: FA0028 (Box 3, Vhs FA0028)
  - Lust for Life: The Writings of Kathy Acker: Panel 5, 2003; ID: FA0029 (Box 3, Vhs FA0029)
  - Fales Library Reading: Anti-War Poetry Reading, February 12, 2003; ID: FA0030 (Box 3, Vhs FA0030)
  - Visions for a Changing Theatre: Panel 1-Seeking Paradise, Ocotober 9, 2003; ID: FA0031 (Box 3, Vhs FA0031A, Vhs FA0031B)
  - Visions for a Changing Theatre: Panel 2-Eyeing Parnassus, Ocotober 9, 2003; ID: FA0032 (Box 3, Vhs FA0032)
  - Visions for a Changing Theatre: Panel 3-Decoding Utopia, Ocotober 9, 2003; ID: FA0033 (Box 3, Vhs FA0033A, Vhs FA0033B)
  - Visions for a Changing Theatre: Panel 4-Making Waves, Ocotober 9, 2003; ID: FA0086 (Box 7, Dvd FA0086)
  - Fales Event Up is Up But So Is Down; Downtown Lit, October 26, 2006; ID: FA0037 (Box 4, Dvd FA0037)
  - Dennis Cooper: Enter at One's Own Risk, Transgressive Writing, March 1, 2007; ID: FA0040 (Box 4, Dvd FA0040)
  - The Fales Collection at the Elmer Holmes Bobst Library; Writing New York: Tales from Gotham City, April 17, 2007; ID: FA0042 (Box 4, Dvd FA0042)
  - Orphan 6: SAMMA Demonstration - Clips, March 29, 2008; ID: FA0046 (Box 8, Dvd FA0046, Box 3, Digital betacam FA0045)
  - Moving / Images: Preserving Downtown Time-Based Works - Video Clips, April 3, 2008; ID: FA0048 (Box 8, Dvd FA0048, Box 3, Betamax FA0047)
  - Moving / Images: Preserving Downtown Time-Based Works - "Signal Loss: Saving Downtown Video", April 4, 2008; ID: FA0049 (Box 8, Dvd FA0049)
  - Moving / Images: Preserving Downtown Time-Based Works - "Not Your Home Movies: Downtown Film", April 4, 2008; ID: FA0050 (Box 8, Dvd FA0050)
  - Moving / Images: Preserving Downtown Time-Based Works - "Not Your Home Movies: Downtown Film", April 4, 2008; ID: FA0051 (Box Shared Fales 123, Audiocassette FA0051)
    Format: Audiocassette
  - Moving / Images: Preserving Downtown Time-Based Works - "Not Your Home Movies: Downtown Film", April 4, 2008; ID: FA0052 (Box Shared Fales 123, Audiocassette FA0052)
  - Fales Series - How A.I.R. Changed the World, September 16, 2008; ID: FA0054 (Box 8, Dvd FA0054)
  - A.I.R. Gallery The History Show, November 18, 2008; ID: FA0056 (Box 8, Dvd FA0056)
  - 2009 Fales Lecture in English and American Literature: "Is There a Future for the Literary Novel?, April 14, 2009; ID: FA0062 (Box 8, Dvd FA0062)
  - The Unbearables - Readings from The Worst Book I Ever Read, September 27, 2009; ID: FA0065 (Box 7, Dvd FA0065)
  - The Children of Burroughs - New York Arts and Legacy of Naked Lunch, October 8, 2009; ID: FA0066 (Box Shared Fales 016, Dvd FA0066)
  - You Are Cordially Invited: The Art and Influence of Robert Blanchon, January 2, 2010; ID: FA0070 (Box 6, Dvd FA0070)
  - Fales: New Media, March 25, 2010; ID: FA0071 (Box 6, Dvd FA0071)
  - Where is Ana Mendieta? (at Tisch School of the Arts), October 7, 2010; ID: FA0073 (Box 6, Dvd FA0073)
  - At Moments Like These He Feels Furthest Away, January 26, 2011; ID: FA0075 (Box 6, Dvd FA0075)
  - Mary Ellen Solt: Toward a Theory of Concrete Poetry, October 27, 2010; ID: FA0076 (Box 6, Dvd FA0076)
  - Visual AIDS: "What Comes Next?", April 20, 2011; ID: FA0078 (Box 6, Dvd FA0078)
  - Fluxus Conversation: Ben Kinmont and Julia Robinson, September 16, 2011; ID: FA0079 (Box 6, Dvd FA0079)
  - Fluxus Amongst Us: Insight and Transformation in Fluxus Encounters, Part I, October 18, 2011; ID: FA0080 (Box 6, Dvd FA0080)
  - Fluxus Amongst Us: Insight and Transformation in Fluxus Encounters, Part II, October 18, 2011; ID: FA0081 (Box 6, Dvd FA0081)
  - Paper Tiger, February 3, 2012; ID: FA0082 (Box 6, Dvd FA0082)
    File Plan
  - Henry Abelove Symposium, February 16, 2012; ID: FA0083 (Box 6, Dvd FA0083)
    Related Materials
  - Dievs Lecture, April 12, 2012; ID: FA0084 (Box 6, Dvd FA0084)
  - Frank Moore: Together in Art and Activism, September 24, 2012; ID: FA0085 (Box 7, Dvd FA0085)
  - Nelson Sullivan: Vlogging in the 80s, April 25, 2013; ID: FA0091 (Box 5, Dvd FA0091a, Dvd FA0091b)
  - Catherine Opie, September 12, 2013; ID: FA0093 (Box 5, Dvd FA0093a, Dvd FA0093b)
  - Sterling Lord, October 24, 2013; ID: FA0094 (Box 5, Dvd FA0094a, Dvd FA0094b)
  - Whither Collectiong? New Visions for Special Collections in the 21st Century, November 20, 2013; ID: FA0095 (Box 5, Dvd FA0095a, Dvd FA0095b, Dvd FA0095c)
  - Duncan & Jess: Between Fields, March 6, 14; ID: FA0097 (Box 5, Dvd FA0097a, Dvd FA0097b, Dvd FA0097c)
  - GoNightclubbing, March 20, 2014; ID: FA0099 (Box 5, Dvd FA0099c, Dvd FA0099a, Dvd FA0099b)
  - Books as Social Media, April 2, 2014; ID: FA0100 (Box 5, Dvd FA0100c, Dvd FA0100a, Dvd FA0100b)
  - Dismantling Invisibility, May 4, 2015; ID: FA0103; 3 media elements (Box 7, Dvd FA0103)
    Format: Playable DVD and Data DVD
  - Celebration of Linda Montano, April 14, 2015; ID: FA0104; 3 media elements (Box 7, Dvd FA0104)
  - Charles Walters: The Director Who Made Hollywood Dance, February 12, 2015; ID: FA0105; 3 media elements (Box 7, Dvd FA0105)
  - Off-Off Broadway's Origins at Caffé Cino, March 11, 2015; ID: FA0107; 3 media elements (Box 7, Dvd FA0107)
  - Fales Lecture in English & American Literature: Histories of the Alphabet, April 1, 2015; ID: FA0109 (Box 7, Dvd FA0109)
- Series II: Fales Food Studies Events, 2005-2015; 3.75 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 4 manuscript boxes, 1 card box, and 1 shared cassette box; 40 DVDs; 1 VHS; 2 MiniDV
  - Critical Topics; Food Series Pt. 1; Fales Library, May 17, 2005; ID: FA0034 (Box 3, Vhs FA0034)
  - Fales Food Series: Women Who Cook for a Living, June 14, 2006; ID: FA0035 (Box 4, Dvd FA0035)
  - Food Series: The Chains and Systems of Food, October 19, 2006; ID: FA0036 (Box 4, Dvd FA0036)
  - Fales Food Series: A Celebration of the Publication of the United States of Arugala David Kamp, October 26, 2006; ID: FA0038 (Box 4, Dvd FA0038)
  - Fales Food Series: What's With All These Books on Food?, December 12, 2006; ID: FA0039 (Box 4, Dvd FA0039)
  - Fales Food Series: Cooking with Color, March 8, 2007; ID: FA0041 (Box 4, Dvd FA0041)
  - Fales Food Series: Building a Food Professional Pedigree: The New Roads to Knowledge and Success, June 14, 2007; ID: FA0043 (Box 8, Dvd FA0043)
  - Fales Food Series: Cooks Who Grow Their Own: A More Direct Route From Earth to Table, October 11, 2007; ID: FA0044 (Box 8, Dvd FA0044)
  - Fales Food Series: The Power of the Pen: The Role of Editors in Writings on Food, March 13, 2008; ID: FA0053 (Box 8, Dvd FA0053)
  - Fales Food Series Emerging and Disappearing: Immigrant Foodways, October 16, 2008; ID: FA0055 (Box 8, Dvd FA0055)
  - Fales Food Series: A Reading and Celebration of American Cheeses by Clark Wolf, December 3, 2008; ID: FA0057 (Box 8, Dvd FA0057)
  - Fales Food Series: "The Enduring Impact and Influence of James Beard on American Food", May 1, 2008; ID: FA0058 (Box 8, Dvd FA0058)
  - Fales Food Series: "Water: A Global Discussion of a Critical Topic", June 5, 2008; ID: FA0059 (Box 8, Dvd FA0059)
  - Fales Food Series: "20 Years of Food Arts; 30 Years of Food and Wine: How Food and Food Writing Have Changed in America, November 20, 2008; ID: FA0060 (Box 8, Dvd FA0060)
  - Fales Food Series: "Food and Celebration: A Long History of What Brings Us Together", March 5, 2009; ID: FA0061 (Box 8, Dvd FA0061)
  - Fales Food Series: New York Farm Connections: The Five Boroughs as Farmland & Marketplace, June 4, 2009; ID: FA0063 (Box 7, Dvd FA0063)
  - Fales Food Series: Food Show: When Performance Becomes Lunch, October 15, 2009; ID: FA0067 (Box Shared Fales 016, Dvd FA0067)
  - Fales Food Series: Who's Who and What's What: The Evolution of the Food Cognoscenti in America, November 5, 2009; ID: FA0068 (Box Shared Fales 016, Dvd FA0068)
  - Fales Food Series: Why (and exactly how) New York Simply Loves Italian, February 3, 2009; ID: FA0069 (Box Shared Fales 016, Dvd FA0069)
  - Fales Food Series: Me In A Book With Recipes, 2010; ID: FA0072 (Box 6, Dvd FA0072)
  - Fales Food Series: Back Into the Kitchen, November 4, 2010; ID: FA0074 (Box 6, Dvd FA0074)
  - Fales Food Series: Harvesting the Roots of Today's Farming and Artisan Cookery Through Oral History, June 9, 2011; ID: FA 0077 (Box 6, Dvd FA0077)
  - Fales Food Series: Changing the American Plate: "The Meat of the Matter", October 20, 2011; ID: FA0087 (Box 7, Dvd FA0087)
  - Fales Food Series: Yelp? Help!, March 14, 2012; ID: FA0088 (Box 7, Dvd FA0088)
  - Fales Food Series: Fales Food Fight: A Closer Look at the 2012 Farm Bill, May 3, 2012; ID: FA0089 (Box 7, Dvd FA0089)
  - Fales Food Series: The Cookbook Book: Why Books and Benchmarks Matter, October 25, 2012; ID: FA0090 (Box 7, Dvd FA0090)
  - Fales Food Series: Food Politics, May 30, 2013; ID: FA0092 (Box 5, Dvd FA0092a, Dvd FA0092b)
  - Fales Food Series: Why Cookbooks Still Matter, December 4, 2013; ID: FA0096 (Box 5, Dvd FA0096a, Dvd FA0096b, Dvd FA0096c)
  - Fales Food Series: Looking Back to Go Forward Ancient Ways in Modern Food, March 13, 2014; ID: FA0098 (Box 5, Dvd FA0098a, Dvd FA0098b, Dvd FA0098c, Dvd FA0098d)
  - Fales Food Series: In Your Glass! The Evolution of Libtation at the American Table, June 5, 2014; ID: FA0101 (Box 5, Dvd FA0101c, Dvd FA0101a, Dvd FA0101b)
  - Fales Food Series: What Exactly is Cooking?, June 4, 2015; ID: FA0102; 3 media elements (Box 7, Dvd FA0102)
  - Fales Food Series: Food in the 21st Century, October 9, 2014; ID: FA0106; 2 media elements (Case FA0106)
    Custodial History
    As of March 2025, this item is missing.
  - Fales Food Series: What is Sustainability Exactly?, April 2, 2015; ID: FA0108; 3 media elements (Case FA0108)